The radiance of the night shines through my window
but the path to immortality is long.
The Eight Views and Nine-Bend Streams are desolate.
Living beings question the miseries of the world over a jar of wine.
Forget about Nirvana and rebirth,
I will break through the waves with my own flesh and blood.
The heavens are vast, so what if I was born mediocre ?
I stare at the Dao in my moments of madness
as the storm rages just below.
I've been thinking about life and death in my dreams.
I've unsheathed my sword to ask the immortals
why the world is a-changing.
Heaven and earth reveals its poignant truths.
Swallow the Four Seas and the Eight Wastelands,
experience all the vicissitudes of life in an instant.
I will defy the light in the sky
to continue to write a new chapter for all things in the three realms of existence.
Just a thought separates mortal from immortal.
Transform your insignificant body into light.
The hardships of the journey
will temper this young man's heart.
If I become a Renegade Immortal, will I hesitate to fight the heavens ?
Renegade Immortal
Subtitles by Bonobosubs
https://discord.gg/Ceckd4pdVA
The teleportation formation 40 000 li east of here
leads directly to Zhao.
There's no god statue here.
Everything changes one day,
it's just a matter of time.
There's a shabby temple here.
Let's sleep here tonight.
Let's go.
Just for one night then.
My god,
this damn weather.
The monks of this temple are all gone
but the mortals disturbed its tranquility.
Doesn't fellow cultivator feel they broke the mood of this rainy night ?
This person saw through me at a glance
but I cannot see through his cultivation.
He isn't simple.
Don't be so nervous.
Mo Zhi
My name is Mo Zhi.
And you are...
Someone from the mountains,
I don't have a name.
Call me Ceng Niu.
Brother Ceng Niu...
Why don't the two of us sit down and talk about the Dao on this rainy night ?
Not a bad idea, right ?
What do you think ?
Brother Ceng Niu's cultivation is shocking.
If I'm not seeing wrong,
you're close to obtaining your domain,
you have the right state of mind.
What in the world are you two talking about ?
Are you guys crazy ?
Sir, what you said is right !
Your use of the word "crazy" is excellent !
If one isn't crazy,
why would they try to understand the heavens ?
why would they try to become an Immortal ?!
One must want something
in order to obtain it.
That's the truth of the world !
I didn't understand a single word,
he really is crazy.
Does Brother Ceng understand ?
Your words are too mysterious.
I don't understand them.
But I think the word "crazy" is not good.
Instead, the word "obsessive" is better.
Wonderful.
Wonderful !
If us cultivators weren't obsessive
then how could we go down the right path
to understand the law of the heavens ?
Just now...
where were... we at ?
He really is crazy !
That's it,
he's insane, really.
There are all sorts of people, that's all.
Well, I forgot.
My name is Mo Zhi.
How should I call you ?
Ceng Niu.
The mood of this rainy night
is endlessly beautiful.
The plants silently absorb the humidity
and the scent of death on them quietly disappears.
This is the beauty of the rain and the taste of Life.
What does Brother Mo think Life is ?
Mortals often say that
Life is a fire.
So maybe this fire here
is Life.
Then
what is Death ?
I don't know how Brother is called.
His name is Ceng Niu !
How many time has he said that ?
Yeah.
Even I remember what they said.
Ever since I obtained my domain,
my memory has been a mess.
Brother Ceng Niu, forgive me.
May I ask
what kind of domain Brother understood ?
Since Brother Mo is showing me his domain,
aren't you afraid I would try to steal it ?
You pursue a way higher domain,
I doubt my lowly Forget Domain can move you.
Brother Mo is being modest.
This domain
is above average.
Although my domain is above average,
there are higher levels of domains.
There are only 2 ways to obtain a domain.
The first one is to imitate the domain of another,
the second is to comprehend the heavens to form your own domain.
Although both methods will achieve Soul Formation,
the difference in realms is huge.
Whether it's in power or potential,
the first method is inferior.
But cultivators who can understand their own domain
are very rare.
To reach Soul Formation,
imitating is the common way.
But you are different.
Brother Ceng Niu,
you will achieve great things in the future.
You haven't answered what Death is yet,
please continue !
Yes,
What's Death...
it was getting interesting.
Death is to die.
If a person dies, it is Death.
If the heart dies, it forgets.
That's right,
Death is a state of forgetfulness.
If a person dies, it is Death.
If the heart dies, then it forgets…
The water falling in this puddle today
makes the puddle come to Life.
Tomorrow, when the rain will be over,
this puddle will become Death.
This temple was alive
when there was a god statue here.
Now that it's gone,
it is dead.
On this rainy night
I don't look at the sky,
the earth,
or the rain itself
but at the raindrop's entire life.
Brother Ceng Niu,
either you understand
or you don't.
Take care of yourself.
Fire lights up then vanishes.
Rains comes and falls.
Everything in this world
experiences Life and Death.
I've been thinking about Life and Death for decades
but I just realized now
A raindrop is born in the sky
and dies on the earth.
that a raindrop is born in the sky
The process of falling in the middle
is its life.
This is Life and Death.
A realm that belongs to me, Wang Lin.
My Life and Death Domain.
Country of Zhao
The last time I was here,
I reached the 15th layer of Qi Condensation.
Now,
I will reach Soul Formation here.
My avatar has reached peak Nascent Soul,
but because of the Ji Realm
my original body is stuck at peak Core Formation.
If I want to reach Soul Formation,
I must dissociate the cultivations of the two bodies.
Before I reach a higher level of cultivation
my bodies can only be merged temporarily.
In that case,
the two bodies will cultivate separately.
The original body will cultivate
to reach the heavens
as a body cultivator
by following the path of the Ancient Gods.
To follow the path of the Ancient Gods,
I first need to shatter my cultivation.
No problem.
I fell out of Core Formation...
Continue !
Now's the time,
to extract the Ji !
The Ji Realm has been refined into an artifact.
It has no use for me anymore.
Give me the beads of killing intent.
A body reconstruction...
These pills will help !
Wang Lin's original body
2-stars Ancient God
Congratulations
on completing the second body reconstruction.
I can't stay here for too long.
If someone finds out that I cultivate the path of the Ancient Gods,
it will be a disaster.
I will sink into the earth,
to face the pressure of the planet core.
The path of the Ancient Gods
is a solitary path.
The cultivation path
is also a dangerous one.
Soul Formation...
Life and Death Domain...
Come !
Why is it so dark ?
Master !
Wang Zhuo's reincarnation
Late stage Foundation Establishment
I felt my heart shake.
Now the sky has suddenly changed colors...
Is there something big going on ?
Someone is reaching Soul Formation here ?
Who is making a breakthrough here ?
I don't know.
But he must be related to Zhao.
During a Soul Formation breakthrough
the spiritual energy gathering is not only helpful for cultivators,
but is also causes the mortals around it to change.
It benefits everyone.
Settle down and meditate.
What is cultivating immortality ?
Mortals
learn to breathe the spiritual energy
to transform their bodies for cultivation.
This is called Foundation Establishment.
After accumulating even more spiritual energy,
they compress it into a Golden Core.
As the core gathers more and more energy, it gives birth to the Nascent Soul.
After reaching Nascent Soul,
one qualifies to fight against the heavens.
But in order to find a way to fight against the heavens,
one needs a a domain, a divine weapon
which wields the power of the heaven and earth.
After the Nascent Soul understands the heavens,
it will become an Origin Soul
that's able to fight against the heavens.
This is how we defy the heavens,
by using their own power.
As long as the Origin Soul lives,
the body is eternal.
So he suceeded in Soul Formation...
The realm that Brother Mo mentioned...
I finally understand.
What a comfortable wind...
Look !
Is an Immortal passing by ?
Wang Lin's avatar
Early stage Soul Formation
Senior,
are you from the country of Zhao ?
Are you willing to stay here 100 years
to allow our country of Zhao to reach rank 4 ?
To strengthen our nation
and resist the invasions of foreigners.
This...
My meridians seem to have opened up !
40 years to reach the Late stage of Foundation Establishment,
not bad.
You are ?
Do you think that carving wood Immortals
You are Wang Zhuo
will help you absorb spiritual energy ?
Xiuxiu, don't be afraid.
I will acompagny you.
When you reach Nascent Soul,
you will remember the past.
But if you remember now,
it will only
bring you pain.
I can't stay here for 100 years
but I planted spirit seeds
which condensed during my breakthrough
in the bodies of 10 people.
Once they reach peak Nascent Soul, I will know
and I will personally come to teach them.
This can protect the country of Zhao
from the assault of rank 3 countries 3 times.
Now do your best.
Thank you, Senior.
The sword sheath that was in my bag of holding
should still be in the void here.
Found it.
A mere ghost magic treasure,
you don’t know your place.
From Life to Death
from Death to Life.
The movement abilities of Soul Formation level
are far more powerful than at Nascent Soul.
Father,
Mother,
I have reached Soul Formation.
When I reach Soul Transformation,
I will be able to wake up Senior Situ.
Maybe then
there will be a way for me to revive you.
Wait for me.
The way to reach Soul Transformation,
besides finding a Soul Transformation Pill,
is to use celestial spiritual energy.
The Celestial Realm is opening soon
and many powerful cultivators are looking forward to it...
It will definitely be
one hell of a fight.
In case you didn't catch it, Ceng Niu was the name of Da Niu's father.
Falling from the night sky and melting into dust
like water without a source.
Like the difference between clouds and mud,
the truth cannot be found in conflict.
Life and death
are like the moment when the rain falls
and like many other unseparable things.
In this lifetime,
to cultivate the truth, cultivate the world first.
Old grudges had to be settled
because half an inch is engraved into my tree rings.
Use the most vivid love and hate
to ask questions to your fate.
Let your eyes be filled enough with rage
to pierce the heart and the soul
then soften because of the mortals' fireworks.
Only when you bend down can you understand
the hidden edge of the blade.
The human mind is nature,
the rain fell silently like an answer.
Life and death are just moments away,
there are many other solutions to grudges.
Use your dusty heart
to depict the world.
One stroke is for killing.
After struggling for hundreds of years, I endured letting go.
One stroke is for caring.
Everywhere there is life, there are thousands of lights.
Give up your mind to be refined
by this endless world.
The human mind is nature,
the rain fell silently like an answer.
Life and death are just moments away,
there are many other solutions to grudges.
Use your dusty heart
to depict the world.
One stroke is for killing.
After struggling for hundreds of years, I endured letting go.
One stroke is for caring.
Everywhere there is life, there are thousands of lights.
Give up your mind to be refined
by this endless world.
Snow falls as my hair turns white, winter withers
while prosperity sprouts in summer.
I step into the world, with light at my fingertips,
the law of cause and effect.
I observe the vastness of heaven and earth so I can get rid of evil.
Obsession arises from one thought, life and death arise from one thought.
Reincarnation is not to be feared.